[
    {
        "question": "What is the length of the train?",
        "options": [
            "120 metres",
            "180 metres",
            "324 metres",
            "150 metres"
        ],
        "answer": "150 metres"
    },
    {
        "question": "A train 125 m long passes a man, running at 5 km/hr in the same direction in which the train is going, in 10 seconds. The speed of the train is:",
        "options": [
            "45 km/hr",
            "50 km/hr",
            "54 km/hr",
            "55 km/hr"
        ],
        "answer": "50 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question": "The length of the bridge, which a train 130 metres long and travelling at 45 km/hr can cross in 30 seconds, is:",
        "options": [
            "200 m",
            "225 m",
            "245 m",
            "250 m"
        ],
        "answer": "245 m"
    },
    {
        "question":"A train is running at a speed of 100Kmph. A car is running on road parallel to the train’s track at a speed of 20 Kmph opposite to train. How much time will it take to cross the car if the length of the train is 100 meters?",
        "options":[
            "5 sec",
            "4 sec",
            "3 sec",
            "3.5 sec"
        ],
        "answer":"3 sec"
    },
    {
        "question":"A boatman takes 3 hours 45 minutes to travel 15 km downstream and takes 2 hours 30 minutes to travel 5 km upstream of a river. What is the speed of the stream of the river in km/h?",
        "options":[
            "2 km/h",
            "1 km/h",
            "6 km/h",
            "4 km/h"
        ],
        "answer":"1 km/h"
    },
    {
        "question":"A speedboat runs 6 km upstream in a river and comes back to the starting point in 33 minutes. The stream of the river is running at 2 km/hr. What is the speed of speedboat in still water?",
        "options":[ 
            "25 km/h", 
            "21 km/h", 
            "26 km/h", 
            "22 km/h"
        ],
        "answer":"22 km/h"
    },
    {
        "question":"A boat runs at the speed of 13 km/h in still water. If the speed of the stream is 4 km/h, how much time will it take to go 68 km downstream?",
        "options":[
            "5 h",
            "4 h",
            "6 h",
            "3 h"
        ],
        "answer":"4 h"
    },
    {
        "question":"A train is running at a speed of 100Kmph. A car is running on road parallel to the train’s track at a speed of 20 Kmph opposite to train. How much time will it take to cross the car if the length of the train is 100 meters?",
        "options":[
            "5 sec",
            "4 sec",
            "3 sec",
            "3.5 sec"
        ],
        "answer":"3 sec"
    },
    {
        "question":"Express 252 as a product of primes.",
        "options":[
            "2 * 2 * 3 * 3 * 7",
            "3* 3 * 3 * 3 * 7",
            "2 * 2 * 2* 3 * 7",
            "2 * 3 * 3 * 3 * 7"
        ],
        "answer":"2 * 2 * 3 * 3 * 7"
    },
    {
        "question":"Find the highest common factor of the following numbers: 4 * 27 * 3125, 8 * 9 * 25 * 7, 16 * 81 * 5 * 11 * 49",
        "options":[
            "180",
            "360",
            "540",
            "1260"
        ],
        "answer":"180"
    },
    {
        "question":"Calculate the HCF of 1.08, 0.36 and 0.9.",
        "options":[
            "0.03","0.9","0.18","0.108"
        ],
        "answer":"0.18"
    },
    {
        "question":"Three numbers are in the ratio 1:2:3 and their HCF is 12. The numbers are:",
        "options":[
            "4, 8, 12",
            "5, 10, 15",
            "10, 20, 30",
            "12, 24, 36"
        ],
        "answer":"12, 24, 36"
    },
    {
        "question":"The sum if two numbers is 528 and their HCF is 33. The number of pairs of numbers satisfying the above condition is:",
        "options":[
            "4","6","8","12"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Three friends started running together on a circular track at 8:00:00 am. Time taken by them to complete one round of the track is 15 min, 20 min, 30 min respectively. If they run continuously without any halts, then at what time will they meet again at the starting point for the fourth time?",
        "options": ["8:30:00 am", "9:00:00 pm", "12:00:00 pm", "12:00:00 am"],
        "answer": "12:00:00 pm"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two numbers are in the ratio 3 : 5. If their L.C.M. is 75, what is the sum of the numbers?",
        "options": ["25", "45", "40", "50"],
        "answer": "40"
    },
    {
        "question": "Three numbers are in the ratio of 2 : 3 : 4 and their L.C.M. is 240. Their H.C.F. is:",
        "options": ["40", "20", "30", "10"],
        "answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the least number which is exactly divisible by 6, 12, 9 and 18?",
        "options": ["96", "36", "24", "81"],
        "answer": "36"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given two numbers x and y such that 1. x^3 + y^3 = 9 2. x + y = 3. Find the value of x^4 + y^4.",
        "options": ["2/3", "7", "13", "17"],
        "answer": "17"
    },
    {
        "question": "The value of x + 1/2x is given as 2, then find the value of 8x^3 + 1/x^3.",
        "options": ["40", "32", "07", "28"],
        "answer": "40"
    },
    {
        "question": "Solve for x in the equation: log(2x - 1) + log(3) = log(x + 5).",
        "options": ["x = -1/3", "x = 1/3", "x = 5/3", "x = 8/5"],
        "answer": "x = 8/5"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the value of b^2 + 1/b^2 = 1, then find the value of b^3 + 1/b^3.",
        "options": ["-1/2", "-1", "-2", "None of the above"],
        "answer": "None of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "Calculate the arithmetic mean of the given series: 2, 6, 10, 14, 18, 22, 26, 30.",
        "options": ["8", "16", "32", "None of the above"],
        "answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the Arithmetic mean of series: 10, 7, 4, 1, -2.",
        "options": ["13/2", "14/3", "4", "16/5"],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Calculate the sum of given series: 1/3, 1/9, 1/27, 1/81.................",
        "options": ["1/4", "1/3", "1/2", "1"],
        "answer": "1/2"
    }
]